Brandon Loveall

Full Stack Developer - Salt Lake City - bloveall02@gmail.com - Portfolio - Github - LinkedIn

Javascript	Node.js	Express.js	HTML5/CSS3	Python	Git/Github
AWS	Typescript	PostgreSQL/SQL	Angular	React/Redux	Unix/Linux

Projects

Conway's Game of Life 9/2022, Devmountain | Demo | Github

React | HTML5/CSS3 | JavsScript

Stylistically simple showcase of the cell simulation "Conway's Game of Life". Visitors are able to place down, clear, and customize the cell grid, in which cells will "simulate" different actions based off a set of rules.

- Rendered with React to cleanly update the cell grid and ensure fast performance
- Created a customizable cell grid with optimized code to minimize rerenders
- Rewrote simulation code to guarantee readability for future updates

Chirper Social Media Site 9/2022, Devmountain | Demo | Github

React | HTML5/CSS3 | JavsScript | PostgreSQL | Express.js | Node.js

Fully functional social media website where users can create an account, make posts, search for and view other profiles, and customize their profile.

- Utilized React to break up the website into 15 modular components
- Implemented a responsive design using CSS for a clean user experience across multiple devices
- Built with practical development principles to maintain functional and readable code

Country API Front End 8/2022, Devmountain | Demo | Github

React | HTML5/CSS3 | JavaScript

Responsive front end display for the REST Countries API in which users are able to query for information on different countries with filters or a search bar.

- Devised an efficient layout for the site given pre-built images of the requested final website
- Improved the loading speed of countries by minimizing API requests and caching results
- Accurately created the final, functional website while only being given images and concept functionality of the requested final product

News Website 7/2022, Devmountain | Demo | Github

React | HTML5/CSS3 | JavsScript | PostgreSOL | Express.is | Node.is

Mock news website where users are able to submit articles and read articles from other users.

- Amplified the user experience by keeping the site layout to a minimum number of elements
- Formed a fully functional front end and back end with clean coding principles
- Revamped the overall design by utilizing flexbox in multiple areas for simple scaling

Development Experience

Full Stack Developer 07/2020-Present

Studying and working with programming languages for 6+ years, studying and working with modern software development frameworks and technologies for 2 years. Continuously building and creating new applications while utilizing all facets of software development to build my expertise within the vast field of computer programming.

Work Experience

Learning Assistant 01/2022-06/2022, Salt Lake Community College

Mentorship role within the Mathematics section of Salt Lake Community College as an in-class tutor Worked with a classroom and was responsible for aiding 24 students in understanding college level mathematics and succeeding in their studies

Mathematics Tutor 09/2021-01/2022, Mathnasium

Mathematics tutor for 50+ students including those studying college level algebra and calculus Created unique problem solving methods for students struggling with comprehension

Education & Certifications

Full Stack Development 05/2022 - 09/2022, Devmountain Associate of Science 2020-2022, Salt Lake Community College GPA 3.7

Member of PTK honor society, awarded the New Century Pathway Transfer Scholarship for academic excellence and service to the community in 2022 (website)